William Tell is a action, adventure, drama film directed by Nick Hamm.
The narrative unfolds in the 14th Century, when the European
nations vie for supremacy within the Holy Roman Empire.
The ambitious Austrian Empire, desiring more land, invades
neighbouring Switzerland, a serene and pastoral nation.
Protagonist William Tell, a formerly peaceful hunter, finds himself forced to take action as his family
and homeland come under threat from the oppressive Austrian King and his ruthless warlords.
William Tell, played by Claes Bang.
Gessler, played by Connor Swindells.
Suna, played by Golshifteh Farahani.
Rudenz, played by Jonah Hauer-King.
Princess Bertha, played by Ellie Bamber.
Stauffacher, played by Rafe Spall.
William Tell is a 2024 epic historical action film written and directed by Nick
Hamm, based on the play of the same name by Friedrich Schiller.
It stars Claes Bang as the titular character, as well as Connor Swindells, Golshifteh Farahani, Jonah
Hauer-King, Tobias Jowett, Ellie Bamber, Rafe Spall, Emily Beecham, Jonathan Pryce, and Ben Kingsley.
The film had its world premiere at the Toronto International Film Festival on 5 September
2024, and was theatrically released in the United Kingdom on 10 January 2025.
It received mixed reviews.
The film explores themes of switzerland, rape and murder,
apple, middle ages (476-1453), medieval.
The tone is emotional.